gfmreview.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

GFM Review is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (which forms part of the Terms of Use of our site) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to our site and not to any third party sites that are linked to from our site.

1\. Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

1.1  Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our service, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information, for example when you enter a competition or promotion, and when you report a problem with our site.

1.2  If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

1.3  We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

1.4  Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders.

1.5  Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

1.6  Any information you provide to us in connection with your use of the forum.

2\. IP addresses and cookies

2.1  We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

A description of the cookies currently used on our site can be accessed via this link.

2.2  For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

                        to estimate our audience size and usage pattern;

                        to store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests;

                        to speed up your searches; and

                        to recognise you when you return to our site.

2.3  You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

2.4  Please note that our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

3\. Where we store your personal data

3.1  The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ('EEA'). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

3.2  Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.  We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

3.3  Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

4\. Uses made of the information

4.1  We use information held about you in the following ways:

                        to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;

                        to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;

                        to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;

                        to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; and

                        to notify you about changes to our service.

4.2  We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by e-mail, post or telephone.

4.3  Where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

4.4  If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data.

4.5  We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users. We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience.

5\. Disclosure of your information

5.1  We may disclose your personal information to any of our associated third parties.

5.2  We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

5.2.1  In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

5.2.2  If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use or relevant terms and conditions of supply of goods, services and/or information and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of our employees, customers, or others.  This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

6\. Your rights

6.1  You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [info@gfmreview.com](mailto:info@gfmreview.com).

6.2  Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

6.3  We may provide you with the opportunity to opt-in to additional newsletters or promotional communications sent by email. If you have opted in or otherwise qualify to receive these forms of communication, and no longer wish to receive our newsletter or other promotional communications by email, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication.

7\. Access to information

The Data Protection Act 1988 gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

8\. Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

9\. Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [info@gfmreview.com](mailto:info@gfmreview.com).

10\. ClickTale

This site also uses ClickTale web analytics service. ClickTale may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as any text you type in this website. ClickTale does not collect personally identifiable information that you do not voluntarily enter in this website. ClickTale does not track your browsing habits across web sites which do not use ClickTale services. For more information see [Privacy Policy for Information Collected by the ClickTale Web Analytics Service](http://www.clicktale.com/privacy_service.aspx). We are using the information collected by ClickTale service to increase our site's usability and make it a more enjoyable experience for you to browse it.

You can choose to disable the service at [http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html](http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html)

11\. Google Analytics & DoubleClick

At an advertiser’s discretion, Google Analytics data may be examined in concert with data about GFM Review ads that have been shown using the Google Display Network or DoubleClick for Advertisers. Thus, GFM Review can understand how anonymous users interacted with the advertiser’s website after seeing GFM Review ads.

                        GFM Review may use this data to inform and optimize our ad campaigns.

                        Users may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/) or

                        Visitors may opt out of our use of Analytics by visiting the [Google Analytics Opt-out page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

12\. Google Analytics & Remarketing

Third party vendors, including Google, may show GFM Review ads on sites on the internet.

                        Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to GFM Review website(s).

                        We may also use analytics data to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website.

                        Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/). In addition, you may also opt out of third party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).
